在上一讲中，我们讨论了机器人正向运动学和正向运动学
In the last lecture, we talked about robot forward kinematics, and forward kinematics
是机器人关节角度之间的关系，我们通过我调用的向量表示
is the relationship between the robot joint angles, which we represent by a vector I call
'Q，以及机器人末端执行器的姿势。
'Q, and the pose of the robot end effector.
我们可以用数学函数来描述这一点。我们可以描述正向运动学
We can describe this in terms of a mathematical function. We can describe forward kinematics
作为机器人关节角度的函数卷曲K，以及该函数的返回值
as the function curly K of the robot joint angles, and the return value of that function
是末端执行器的姿势。这在机器人技术中非常有用，但更有用
is the pose of the end effector. This is very very useful in robotics, but more useful is
什么叫做'反向运动学'。
what's called the 'Inverse Kinematics.'
这个函数告诉我们为了实现一个我们需要的关节角度
This is the function that tells us that joint angles that we need in order to achieve a
特别是机器人末端效应器姿势。
particular robot end effector pose.
所以说我们希望机器人末端效应器在空间中处于这个特定的姿势
So say we want the robots end effector to be at this particular pose in space, then
为了让机器人末端执行器达到特定的姿势，应该将关节角度设置为什么？
what should the joint angles be set to in order for the robot end effector to get to that particular pose?
这被称为“反向运动学问题”，这对臂式机器人来说非常关键。
This is called the 'Inverse Kinematics Problem' that's really key to arm type robots.